*
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
- [growling]
- Why couldn't I see it before?
- [咆哮]
- 为什么我之前看不到？
- [roars]
- [咆哮]
- [laughing maliciously]
- [恶意地笑]
The way to get the Krabby Patty
formula was so obvious.
获取蟹黄饼的方法
公式是如此明显。
Spend an inordinate amount
of time
花费过多的金额
时间的
training several dozen sea bears
to take over your restaurant
训练数十只海熊
接管你的餐馆
and force you
to give it up.
并强迫你
放弃它。
Nothing can turn them
from their central purpose!
没有什么可以改变他们
从他们的中心目标出发！
- Yoo-hoo.
- 哟吼。
Who wants their tummies
tickled?
谁想要自己的肚子
痒痒了吗？
- No! My weapons!
Ouch!
- 不！我的武器！
哎哟!
- Sea bears aren't weapons,
Plankton.
- 海熊不是武器，
浮游生物。
They're furry
buckets of love.
它们毛茸茸的
一桶桶的爱。
[laughs]
See?
[笑]
看到了吗？
And what do sea bears love more
than tummy tickles?
海熊更喜欢什么
比肚子痒？
Jellyfish honey.
海蜇蜜。
Come and get it.
快过来取。
- No, come back!
- 不，回来吧！
- Why do you keep
doing this, Plankton?
- 你为什么保留
做这个吗，浮游生物？
When you mess with me business,
you mess with me money!
当你扰乱我的生意时
你拿我钱来乱搞！
- Money's not everything,
you know?
- 金钱不是万能的
你知道吗？
- Course it is!
- 当然是！
Money makes the world
go round
金钱创造世界
绕圈
and makes me heart
go pound.
让我心动
去磅吧。
- Well, if you love money
so much,
- 好吧，如果你爱钱
就这么多，
why don't you marry it?
你为什么不嫁给它呢？
- If I could,
I would.
- 如果我可以的话
我会的。
- Would you now?
[laughing maliciously]
- 现在你愿意吗？
[恶意大笑]
- You still here?
- Aah!
- 你还在吗？
- 啊啊！
This gives me an idea.
Ow!
这给了我一个想法。
噢！
- [sighs]
- [叹气]
Another lonely evening...
又是一个孤独的夜晚……
dumping trash...alone.
独自倾倒垃圾。
- [crying]
- Huh?
- [哭泣]
- 啊？
- [crying]
- [哭泣]
- Um...
- 嗯...
Hello? Miss?
- [crying]
你好？错过？
- [哭泣]
Ooh, careful now.
Careful.
哦，现在小心点。
小心。
Your ink will run.
你的墨水会流掉。
- My, you're
such a gentleman.
- 天哪，你是
这样的一位绅士。
- [chuckles nervously]
Yeah, well.
- [紧张地笑]
是的，好吧。
So, uh, what's a nice
denomination like you doing...
那么，呃，什么是好的
像你这样的教派...
on a bench like this?
在这样的长凳上？
- My date was supposed
to bring me to the bank,
- 我的约会本来是
带我去银行
but he stood me up.
但他让我站起来。
- What?
- 什么？
Hey, if I met the scallywag
that stood you up,
嘿，如果我遇到了那个恶棍
让你站起来，
I'd knock him down.
我会把他击倒。
Ooh!
哦！
- My knight
in shinning exoskeleton.
- 我的骑士
在闪亮的外骨骼中。
- Name's Krabs,
Eugene Krabs.
- 名字叫螃蟹，
尤金·克拉布斯.
And yours?
你的呢？
- Cashina.
You're very sweet.
- 卡希纳。
你很可爱。
- You know something?
- 你知道什么吗？
You look like a million bucks
when you smile.
你看起来像百万富翁
当你微笑时。
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
- Cashina, would you make
this old crab's day
- Cashina，你会做吗
这个老螃蟹的日子
and allow me to take you
to a place
让我带你去
到一个地方
where you can
buy me dinner?
你可以在哪里
请我吃饭？
- I'd love to.
- 我喜欢。
Scam you out of your
secret formula, that is.
骗你出你的
秘密公式，就是。
[laughing maliciously]
[恶意大笑]
[giggles]
[咯咯笑]
[both chuckling]
[两人都笑了]
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
- Whoa!
- 哇！
- [grunting]
- [咕哝]
- Allow me.
- 请允许我。
- This food is so delicious.
- 这食物真好吃。
Oop, you don't suppose it has
a secret formula.
哎呀，你不认为它有
一个秘密公式。
I don't suppose you know
anything about secrets...
我想你不知道
任何关于秘密的事情...
or formulas.
或公式。
- Ooh, I do have
a very special recipe.
- 哦，我有
一个非常特别的食谱。
- Yes?
- For delicious kisses.
- 是的？
- 美妙的吻。
- Ugh.
- 呃。
- Cashina, would you mind
if I kissed you?
-卡西娜，你介意吗
如果我吻你了？
- Oh, Eugene.
This is all moving so fast.
- 哦，尤金。
这一切进展得如此之快。
Just as I planned.
[laughs]
正如我计划的那样。
[笑]
- Be gentle.
- 温柔点。
- Purse lips.
- 钱包嘴唇。
[electricity zapping]
[电击]
- Wow!
What a woman.
- 哇！
真是个女人啊。
- [groans]
Well, I finally did it.
- [呻吟]
好吧，我终于做到了。
I kissed a crab.
我亲吻了一只螃蟹。
- [laughing happily]
- [开心地笑]
Ooh, Cashina.
哦，卡希纳。
- Daddy, I want to--
Ew!
- 爸爸，我想要--
呃！
Are you kissing a locket
with a woman's picture in it?
你在亲吻吊坠吗
里面有一张女人的照片？
- Oh, no! No!
I was, uh--
- 哦，不！不！
我当时，呃——
I was polishing this jewelry
with me mouth hole.
我正在抛光这件珠宝
与我口洞。
You see? Like this...
[smooching]
你看？像这样...
[接吻]
- Gross!
- 总的！
- Pearl, me little beluga,
- 珍珠，我的小白鲸，
I never thought
I'd say this,
我从没想过
我想说的是，
but I may have found you
a new mom.
但我可能找到了你
一位新妈妈。
- No way!
- 决不！
I have seen stepmoms
in movies, Dad.
我见过继母
在电影里，爸爸。
She'll make me sweep up
the cinders,
她会让我扫地
煤渣，
and then she won't let me go
to the ball,
然后她不会让我走
到球，
and then I'll never meet
my Prince Charming.
然后我就永远不会见面了
我的白马王子。
[crying]
[哭泣]
- You know, we're gonna have
to have another talk
- 你知道，我们将会有
再谈一次
about fantasy and reality.
关于幻想和现实。
- Okay,
then what's she like?
- 好吧，
那她是什么样的人呢？
- Well, she's everything
I've ever wanted in a woman.
- 好吧，她就是一切
我曾经想要一个女人。
- Blech!
- Oh, don't worry, sweetie.
- 布莱奇！
-哦，别担心，亲爱的。
Nothing will ever come
between us.
什么都不会到来
我们之间。
[doorbell rings]
Oh, she's here! Out of me way!
[门铃响]
哦，她来了！别挡我的路！
Hello, me little
money stack.
你好我小
钱栈。
I want you to meet
me daughter, Pearl.
我想让你见见
我的女儿，珀尔。
- Pearl, I love
your rouge.
- 珍珠，我爱
你的胭脂。
How chic!
- It's actually a rash.
多别致啊！
- 这实际上是皮疹。
- Uh...
teen talk, teen talk.
- 呃...
青少年谈话，青少年谈话。
Uh, girls like shoes.
呃，女孩子都喜欢鞋子。
Well, Pearl.
I love your shoes.
嗯，珍珠。
我喜欢你的鞋子。
- I'm not wearing shoes.
- 我没穿鞋。
Those are barnacles.
那些是藤壶。
- Oh, uh,
I have some cream for that.
- 哦，呃，
我有一些奶油。
- Stop trying to mom at me,
lady!
- 别再对我当妈妈了
女士！
I don't need you.
我不需要你。
- Well, Pearl,
since I'm seeing your father,
- 嗯，珍珠，
自从我见到你父亲
I hope we can learn
to understand each other.
我希望我们能够学习
互相理解。
- You'll never
understand me!
- 你永远不会
理解我！
In fact, I'm going
to make it a point
事实上，我要去
使它成为一个要点
to never be
understandable again.
永远不会
又可以理解了。
Blarb snobble goober blab!
胡言乱语势利古柏胡言乱语！
- Eh, let me talk to her.
- No.
- 呃，让我跟她谈谈。
- 不。
I think I should do this alone.
我想我应该独自完成这件事。
- Oh, I haven't been
this nervous
-哦，我没去过
这紧张
since me first boatswain's ball.
自从我第一次参加水手长舞会以来。
- And I was all,
"You call this a mugging?"
- 而我就是全部，
“你管这叫抢劫？”
And then I suplexed him
until he gave me my purse back.
然后我就让他陷入困境
直到他把钱包还给我。
[both laughing]
[两人都笑了]
- Hey, you two,
how about inviting me
- 嘿，你们两个，
邀请我怎么样
into your inside joke, eh?
进入你的内心笑话，嗯？
- Oh, you wouldn't get it,
Dad.
- 哦，你不会明白的，
爸爸。
It's a girl thing.
这是一个女孩的事情。
- Cashina,
you know I love you,
- 卡希纳,
你知道我爱你，
and now me daughter
loves you too.
现在是我的女儿
也爱你。
Will you marry me,
Cashina?
你愿意嫁给我吗
卡什纳？
[romantic music]
[浪漫音乐]
*
- Yes! Yes, yes!
- 是的！是的，是的！
Perfect!
完美的！
When we're married,
当我们结婚的时候，
he'll have to tell me
the secret formula.
他必须告诉我
秘密公式。
[laughs maliciously]
Yeah!
[恶意地笑]
是啊！
- SpongeBob, you're gonna be
me wedding planner.
- 海绵宝宝，你会的
我的婚礼策划师。
- I'm so honored,
Mr. Krabs.
- 我很荣幸
蟹老板。
- Great!
Here's your budget.
- 伟大的！
这是您的预算。
- Mr. Krabs,
I am gonna stretch this dollar
- 蟹老板先生，
我要花点钱
until it begs
for mercy.
直到它乞求
为了怜悯。
No disrespect
to your new bride.
没有不尊重
给你的新新娘。
[upbeat music]
[欢快的音乐]
*
Would you like our house red
or our house yellow?
你想要我们的房子是红色的吗
还是我们的房子是黄色的？
[laughing]
[笑]
Ta-da!
哒哒！
[wedding march]
[婚礼进行曲]
- [clears throat]
- [清喉咙]
And now the couple
will exchange their vows.
而现在这对夫妇
将交换誓言。
- Eugene, you have everything
I ever wanted in a man:
- 尤金，你拥有一切
我曾经想要一个男人：
an exoskeleton,
freakishly long eye stalks,
外骨骼，
长得奇特的眼柄，
and the secret
Krabby Patty formula.
和秘密
蟹黄饼配方。
all: Aw!
全体：噢！
- Cashina,
you came into my life
- 卡希纳,
你进入了我的生活
when I thought I'd live
the rest of it alone.
当我以为我能活着的时候
剩下的就单独说了。
You showed me
once and for all
你向我展示了
一劳永逸
that while money
can't buy you love,
那虽然钱
买不到你的爱，
it can give you love.
它可以给你爱。
all: Aw!
全体：噢！
- You may now
kiss the bride.
- 你现在可以
亲吻新娘。
[both smooching]
[两人接吻]
[all cheering]
[大家欢呼]
- Oh, no!
What about the bouquet?
- 哦，不！
花束呢？
- Uh, one bouquet
coming up, Mrs. Krabs!
- 呃，一束
来了，蟹老板夫人！
all: Huh?
全体：啊？
- Huh?
- 啊？
- Catch!
- 抓住！
[all yelling]
[大家大喊]
- [muffled]
Hooray! I win!
- [低声]
万岁！我赢了！
[burps]
[打嗝]
[all crying]
[都哭了]
- It's a shame
Plankton couldn't be here.
- 真可惜
浮游生物不可能在这里。
- [groaning]
- [呻吟]
Who knew Eugene was
so light on his crab legs?
谁知道尤金是
他的蟹腿这么轻吗？
[retches]
[干呕]
[both giggling]
[两人都咯咯笑]
- Okay.
- 好的。
- [giggles]
- [咯咯笑]
Eugene,
尤金,
I don't want there to be
any secrets between us.
我不想有
我们之间的任何秘密。
- What?
Oh!
- 什么？
哦！
I'll tell you everything,
我会告诉你一切
no matter how embarrassing.
不管多么尴尬。
I wet me bed
till I was 40.
我尿湿了床
直到我40岁。
Me armpits sweat smells like
tartar sauce when I'm afraid.
我腋下有汗味
当我害怕的时候，塔塔酱。
- Not those kinds
of secrets.
- 不是那些类型
的秘密。
- Ooh, okay.
- 哦，好吧。
Whatever you want,
me sweet, just ask.
无论你想要什么，
我亲爱的，就问吧。
- I want you to tell me...
- 我想让你告诉我...
the secret Krabby Patty
formula.
秘密的克拉比帕蒂
公式。
- The what?
- 什么？
- The secret formula
- 秘密配方
is locked away
in your heart.
被锁起来
在你心里。
Unlock your heart
for me, Eugene.
解锁你的心
对我来说，尤金。
Let me in.
让我进去。
- Oh. Okay.
- 哦。好的。
Anything for you,
baby.
为你做任何事，
宝贝。
I'm gonna whisper it
to you,
我会轻声说
对你来说，
just in case there's
any prying ears out there.
以防万一
那里有任何窥探的耳朵。
- Oh, boy.
Here it comes!
- 哦，男孩。
它来了！
- All right, my sweet.
Here it is.
- 好吧，亲爱的。
这里是。
I'm getting a little
emotional here.
我有点
这里有情感。
You know,
I never told anyone
你知道，
我从未告诉过任何人
the secret Krabby Patty
formula before.
秘密的克拉比帕蒂
之前的公式。
So...here goes.
那么...就这样吧。
[electricity zapping]
[电击]
- Come on, Krabs.
Let it all out.
- 来吧，蟹蟹。
把一切都释放出来。
Uh!
- Plankton?
呃！
- 浮游生物？
- No, no! I'm not Plankton.
I'm Cashina.
- 不，不！我不是浮游生物。
我是卡西娜。
[laughs]
Your blushing bride.
[笑]
你的新娘脸红了。
I'm, uh, uh--
am I blushing?
我是，呃，呃——
我脸红了吗？
- You...
- 你...
monster!
怪物！
[grunting]
[咕噜声]
Argh!
啊！
- Y-y-you're not gonna
crush me?
- 你-你-你不会的
压垮我？
- Oh, I've been alone
for so long.
- 哦，我一直孤身一人
这么久了。
And for the first time
in forever,
并且是第一次
在永远，
I felt for someone.
我对某人有感觉。
Well, something.
嗯，有什么。
Well, I mean,
a pile of cash with lips.
嗯，我的意思是，
一堆现金与嘴唇。
It was all
too good to be true.
这就是全部
好得令人难以置信。
Cashina may have not
been real,
卡希纳可能还没有
曾经是真实的，
but me feelings were.
但我的感受是。
Weren't they?
- Get ahold of yourself, Krabs.
不是吗？
- 控制住自己，蟹蟹。
- Plankton, are you saying
it was all just a scheme to you?
- 浮游生物，你是说
这对你来说只是一个计划吗？
You felt nothing?
- You're crazy!
你什么感觉都没有吗？
- 你疯了！
I'm out of here!
我要离开这里了！
And one day, that formula
will be mine!
有一天，这个公式
将是我的！
Mark it!
标记它！
- [weeping]
- [哭泣]
[sobbing]
[抽泣]
- Oh, hey, buddy.
- 哦，嘿，伙计。
I want you to know,
我想让你知道，
even though your wife
just ran out on you,
即使你的妻子
刚刚摆脱了你，
you still have
to tip me.
你还有
给我小费。